<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blips on Kinnaman</title>
    <link>http://kinnaman.net/blip/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blips on Kinnaman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 16:44:17 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://kinnaman.net/blip/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://kinnaman.net/blip/2024-03-01_164416/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 16:44:17 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://kinnaman.net/blip/2024-03-01_164416/</guid>
      <description>I am happy with the tweaking for today. I have other projects I wish to work on. This will suffice for writing notes and making new blog posts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://kinnaman.net/blip/2024-03-01_122209/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 12:22:09 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://kinnaman.net/blip/2024-03-01_122209/</guid>
      <description>I fixed a bug I was running into on my own system with regard to my &amp;ldquo;blip.sh&amp;rdquo; script. This taught me to test my inputs before executing a script without making assumptions about the system. Still, my blog post files didn&amp;rsquo;t work on windows because they had the incorrect naming schema. Apparently, Windows doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow colons in the name. So I used tr which translates or deletes characters to loop through the file names and remove all the colons.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://kinnaman.net/blip/2024-03-01_120604/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 12:06:05 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://kinnaman.net/blip/2024-03-01_120604/</guid>
      <description>I finally have WSL set up on my new desktop. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t fun reinstalling all my programs and moving my data, but I&amp;rsquo;m glad it&amp;rsquo;s finally finished. Now I&amp;rsquo;m working on my flight sim blog post and some other fun activities. Perhaps I will update how my build went and other thoughts about Windows.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://kinnaman.net/blip/2023-12-04_042705/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 04:27:08 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://kinnaman.net/blip/2023-12-04_042705/</guid>
      <description>Virtually all of my electronics are old but well running, which is both great and frustrating. It means justifying purchasing new PC parts, cameras, or cell phones is impossible. However it does mean I save money and can wait longer to buy something new down the road, which means better hardware for the same price. Most of my gripes about the hardware I currently own simply revolve around gaming, especially for portability or playing demanding titles.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://kinnaman.net/blip/2023-10-26_191734/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 19:17:37 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://kinnaman.net/blip/2023-10-26_191734/</guid>
      <description>I am starting job applications for software engineering and devops positions. In the meanwhile I will continue doing both web and game design within my personal time. Thankfully my career in IT still engages me, so I will continue studying networking and sysadmin skills for fun if I do change roles in tech.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://kinnaman.net/blip/2023-10-25_124356/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 12:44:02 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://kinnaman.net/blip/2023-10-25_124356/</guid>
      <description>Today I&amp;rsquo;m trying to set up my server on an ARM single board computer. I have an H616 based android TV box that I want to repurpose for email and web hosting. I&amp;rsquo;m flashing a micro-SD card at a coffee shop so it&amp;rsquo;ll be awhile before I can troubleshoot any potential hiccups that it ran into. There are several repositories I&amp;rsquo;ve found for Armbian, but the one labled as H616 is well worth a try.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://kinnaman.net/blip/2023-10-23_225047/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 22:50:47 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://kinnaman.net/blip/2023-10-23_225047/</guid>
      <description>I successfully added blips to my blog. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty happy with that. While doing the edits tonight, it is clear my Neovim configs need an update as well. But it&amp;rsquo;s getting late so I&amp;rsquo;ll postpone that for now. It isn&amp;rsquo;t good to become sidetracked so quickly.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://kinnaman.net/blip/2023-10-23_221156/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 22:11:56 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://kinnaman.net/blip/2023-10-23_221156/</guid>
      <description>Time to add the blip section to my blog&amp;rsquo;s nav. Actually customizing it and adding it as a sub-menu item will come later.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://kinnaman.net/blip/2023-10-23_220305/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 22:03:05 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://kinnaman.net/blip/2023-10-23_220305/</guid>
      <description>Found a few nice little animations for websites like like this handwritten animation, a nice submit button, perlin art, and some decent svg art</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://kinnaman.net/blip/2023-10-23_195028/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 19:50:31 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://kinnaman.net/blip/2023-10-23_195028/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m getting a little tired of creating blips using the full ./blip.sh typeout. I would rather be able to write &amp;ldquo;blip&amp;rdquo; in the terminal, so I&amp;rsquo;m adding it to my .bashrc</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://kinnaman.net/blip/2023-10-23_194704/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 19:47:04 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://kinnaman.net/blip/2023-10-23_194704/</guid>
      <description>Rewatching the 2004 Van Helsing. It reminds me of World of Warcraft&amp;rsquo;s worgen. I think I&amp;rsquo;ll resubscribe to play more of Dragonflight. I was having fun with that expansion but ran out of time to play.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://kinnaman.net/blip/2023-10-22_190959/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2023 19:10:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://kinnaman.net/blip/2023-10-22_190959/</guid>
      <description>After trying the Quest 3 at Bestbuy, I was set on purchasing a Quest for home gaming and to tinker with. So yesterday I purchased the Quest 2, as I do not have a great desire for the XR features yet and it would be ~$200 less to purchase. I was wrong to choose the older model, as I quickly felt nausea while using the Quest 2. I&amp;rsquo;m going to return the Quest 2 and spend the extra for the Quest 3.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://kinnaman.net/blip/2023-10-21_071256/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2023 07:12:56 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://kinnaman.net/blip/2023-10-21_071256/</guid>
      <description>Now that the content generation workflow for blips is streamlined, I need to create their own layouts. That will be for this evening or another day as I have to get ready for work.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://kinnaman.net/blip/2023-10-21_070329/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2023 07:03:29 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://kinnaman.net/blip/2023-10-21_070329/</guid>
      <description>Made a simple bash script for creating blips in linux.&#xA;#! /bin/bash DATE=$(date +%F) TIME=$(date +%T) FILE_NAME=$DATE\_$TIME.md hugo new blip/$FILE_NAME $EDITOR content/blip/$FILE_NAME </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://kinnaman.net/blip/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2023 06:32:43 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://kinnaman.net/blip/2/</guid>
      <description>I like the blips or &amp;lsquo;micro posts&amp;rsquo; idea. I just need a script to create the filenames as labelling them 1.md, 2.md, 3.md, etc. is inefficient.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://kinnaman.net/blip/a/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 23:43:32 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://kinnaman.net/blip/a/</guid>
      <description>I created a &amp;lsquo;blips&amp;rsquo; directory to be used similarly to how Twitter or Threads is intended. Quick little posts of passing thoughts without much effort. I&amp;rsquo;m grateful that creating static websites and blogs has become so accessible. Throughout my time in IT, I&amp;rsquo;ve learned that digital literacy in the general public is much lower than a younger me would have guessed. That&amp;rsquo;s okay though as it has been for both work and pleasure to help others with troubleshooting or translating the technical jargon to simpler language.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
